College English Test, Band 6,
Part 2, Listening Comprehension.
Section A, Directions.
this section, you will hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
centre. Jack, sit down and listen.
This is important.
We'll have to tackle the problems of exporting step by step and the first move is to
get an up -date picture of where we stand now.
Why don't we just concentrate on expanding here at home?
Of course, we should hold on to our position here, but you must admit the market
here is limited.
Yes, but it's safe.
The government keeps out foreigners with import controls.
Though I must admit, I feel sure we could hold our own against foreign bikes.
I agree. That's why I'm suggesting exporting, because I feel we can compete with the
best of them.
you are really saying is that we'd make more profit by selling bikes abroad where we
have a cost advantage and can charge higher prices.
Exactly. But wait a minute.
Packaging, shipping, financing, etc.
will push up our costs and we could end up no better off, maybe worse off.
Okay, now there are extra costs involved, but if we do it right, they can be built
into the price of the bike and we can still be competitive.
How sure are you about our chances of success in the foreign market?
That's the sticky one.
It's going to need a lot of research.
I'm hoping to get your help.
Come on, Jack.
Is it worth it or not?
There'll be a lot of problems.
Nothing we can't handle.
I'm not that hopeful.
But yes, I think we should go ahead with a feasibility study.
Marvelous, Jack. I was hoping you'd be on my side.
1 to 4 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 1. What does the woman intend to do?
Question 2. Why does the man think it's safe to focus on the home market?
Question 3. What is the man's concern about selling bikes abroad?
Question 4. What do the speakers agree to do?
Conversation 2. What does the term alternative energy source mean?
When we think of energy or fuel for our homes and cars, we think of petroleum, a
fossil fuel processed from oil removed from the ground of which there is a limited
supply. But alternative fuels can be many things.
Wind, sun, and water can can all be used to create fuel.
Is the threat of running out of petroleum real?
It has taken thousands of years to create the natural stores of petroleum we have
now. We are using what is available at a much faster rate than it is being produced
over time. The real controversy surrounding the amounts of petroleum we have is how
much we need to keep in reserve for future use.
Most experts agree that by around 2025, the amount of petroleum we use will reach a
peak, then production and availability will begin to seriously decline.
This is not to say there will be no petroleum at this point, but it will become very
difficult and therefore expensive to extract.
Is that the most important reason to develop alternative fuel and energy sources?
There two very clear reasons to do so.
One is that whether we have 60 or 600 years of fossil fuels left, we have to find
other fuel sources eventually, so the sooner we start, the better off we will be.
The other big argument is that when you burn fossil fuels, you release substances
trapped in the ground for a long time, which leads to some long -term negative
effects like global warming and the greenhouse effect.
Questions 5 to 8 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 5. do we usually refer to when we talk about energy according to the man?
Question 6. What do most experts agree on according to the man?
Question 7. What does the man think we should do now?
Question 8. How do fossil fuels affect the environment?
Section B. Directions.
In this section, you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
centre. Passage 1.
Karen Smith is a buyer for a department store in New York.
Department store buyers purchase the goods that their stores sell.
They not only have to know what is at the moment but also have to guess what will
become fashionable next season or next year.
Most buyers work for just one department in a store, but the goods that Karen finds
may be displayed and sold in several different sections of the store.
Her job involves buying handicrafts from all over the world.
Last year, she made a trip to Morocco and returned with rugs, pots, dishes, and
pans. The year before, she visited Mexico and bought back handmade tablecloths,
mirrors with frames of tin, and paper flowers.
The paper flowers are bright and colourful, so they were used to decorate the whole
store. This year, Karen is travelling in Malaysia, Thailand, and Indonesia.
Many of countries that Karen visits have government offices that promote
handicrafts. The officials are glad to cooperate with her by showing her the
products that are available.
Karen especially likes to visit markets in small towns and villages whenever she can
arrange for it.
She is always looking for interesting and unusual items.
Karen thinks she has the best job she could have found.
She loves all the travelling that she has to do, because she often visits markets in
small, out -of -the places.
She sees much more of the countries she visits than an ordinary tourist would.
As soon as she gets back to New York from one trip, Karen begins to plan another.
9 to 11 are based on the passage you have just heard.
What is said to make a good department store buyer?
What does Karen's job involve?
Question 11. Why does Karen think she has got the best job?
Question 11. job?
Passage 2. Mark felt that it was time for him to take part in his community, so he
went to the neighborhood meeting after work.
The area's city councilwoman was leading a discussion about how the quality of life
was on the decline.
The neighborhood faced many problems.
Mark looked at the charts taped to the walls.
There were charts for parking problems, crime, and for problems in vacant buildings.
Mark read from the charts.
Police patrols cut back.
Illegal parking up 20%.
People were supposed to suggest solutions to the councilwoman.
It was too much for Mark.
The problems are too big, he thought.
He turned to the man next to him and said, I think this is a waste of my time.
Nothing I could do would make a difference here.
As he neared the bus stop on his way home, Mark saw a woman carrying a grocery bag
and a baby.
As Mark got closer, her other child, a little boy, suddenly darted into the street.
The woman tried to reach for him, but as she moved, her bag shifted and groceries
started to fall out.
Mark ran to take the boy's arm and led him back to his mother.
You got to stay with Mom, he said.
Then he picked up the stray groceries while the woman smiled in relief.
Thanks, she said.
You've got great timing.
Just being neighborly, Mark said.
As he rode home, he glanced at the poster near his seat in the bus.
Small acts of kindness add up.
Mark smiled and thought, maybe that's a good place to start.
Questions 12 to 15 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 12 What did Mark think he should start doing?
Question 13 What was being discussed when Mark arrived at the neighborhood meeting?
Question 14 What did Mark think of the community's problems?
Question 15 Why did Mark smile on his ride home?
Question Question 15 15 ride Question
Section C Directions In this section, you will hear three recordings of lectures or
talks, followed by three or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1, with a single line through the
center. Recording 1
Industrialization came to the United States after 1790, as North American
entrepreneurs increased productivity by reorganizing work and building factories.
These innovations in manufacturing boosted output and living standards to an
unprecedented extent. The average per capita wealth increased by nearly 1 per year,
30 over the course of a generation.
Goods had once been luxury items became part of everyday life.
The impressive gain in output stemmed primarily from the change of the way in which
workers made goods.
Since the 1790s, North American entrepreneurs, even without technological
improvements, had broadened the scope of the work system that made manufacturing
more efficient by distributing materials to a succession of workers who each
performed a single step of the production process.
For example, during the 1820s and 1830s, the shoe industry greatly expanded the
scale and extent of the work system.
Tens of thousands of rural women, paid according to the amount they produced,
fabricated the uppers of shoes, which were bound to the soles by skilled shoemakers
in dozens of Massachusetts towns, whereas previously skilled shoemakers would have
made the entire shoe.
This system of production made the employer a powerful shoe boss, and eroded
workers' control over the pace and conditions of labor.
However, it also dramatically increased the output of shoes while cutting the price.
Entrepreneurs created an even more important new organization, the Modern Factory,
which used power -driven machines and assembly line techniques to turn out large
quantities of well -made goods.
As early as 1782, the creative inventor Oliver Evans had built a highly automated
labor -saving flour mill driven by water power.
His machinery lifted the grain to the top of the cleaned it as it fell into
containers known as hoppers,
ground the grain into flour, and then conveyed the flour back to the top of the mill
to allow it to cool as it descended into barrels.
Subsequently, manufacturers made use of new improved stationary steam engines to
power their mills.
This new technology enabled them to build factories in the nation's largest cities,
taking advantage of urban inexpensive labor, good transportation networks, and eager
customers. Questions 16 to 19 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 16. What is the talk mainly about?
Question 17. Why does the speaker mention the shoe industry?
Question 18. According to the talk, how did later mills differ from the
Question 19. Which of the following is mentioned as a result of improvements in
factory machinery?
Question 19. Recording 2 The economic depression in the late 19th century United
States contributed significantly to a growing movement in literature toward realism
and naturalism. After the 1870s, a number of important authors began to reject the
romanticism that had prevailed immediately following the Civil War of 1861 to 1865,
and turned instead to realism.
Determined to portray life as it was, with loyalty to real life and accurate
representation without any idealization, they studied local dialects, wrote stories
which focused on life in specific regions of the country, and emphasized the true
relationships between people.
In doing so, they reflected broader trends in the society, such as
industrialization, evolutionary theory, which emphasized the effect of the
environment on humans, and the influence of science.
Realists such as Joel Chandler Harris and Ellen Glasgow depicted life in the South,
Hamlin Garland described life on the Great Plains, and Sarah Orne Jewett wrote about
everyday life in rural New England.
Another realist, Brett Hart, achieved fame with stories that portrayed local life in
the California mining camps.
Samuel Clemens, who adopted the pen name Mark Twain, became the country's most
outstanding realist author, observing life around him with a humorous and skeptical
eye. In his stories and novels, Twain drew on his own experiences, and used dialect
and common speech instead of literary language, touching off a major change in
American prose style.
Other writers became impatient even with realism.
Pushing evolutionary theory to its limits, they wrote of a world in which a cruel
and merciless environment determined human fate.
These writers, called naturalists, often focused on economic hardship, studying
people struggling with poverty, and other aspects of urban and industrial life.
Naturalists brought to their writing a passion for direct and honest experience.
Theodore Dreiser, the foremost naturalist writer, in novels such as Sister Carrie,
grimly portrayed a dark world in which human beings were tossed about by forces
beyond their understanding or control.
Dreiser thought that writers should tell the truth about human affairs, not
fabricate romance, and Sister Carrie, he said, was not intended as a piece of
literary craftsmanship, but was a picture of conditions.
Questions 20 to 22 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 20. to the talk, what was a highly significant factor in the development of
realist and naturalist literature?
Question 21. Why is Mark considered as a very important literary figure?
Question 22. What can we learn about Theodore Dreiser according to the talk?
Welcome to Science World.
Today we have Dr.
Michael Hudson, Chief of the Department of Life Science in Boston University.
it is estimated that over 99 of all species that ever existed have become extinct.
What causes extinction?
Well, when a species is no longer adapted to a changed environment, it may perish.
The exact causes of a species' death vary from situation to situation.
addition, rapid ecological change may render an environment hostile to a species.
For example, temperatures may change and a species may not be able to adapt.
Food resources may be affected by environmental changes, which will then cause
problems for a species requiring these resources.
Other species may become better adapted to an environment,
resulting in competition and ultimately in the death of a species.
The fossil record reveals that extinction has occurred throughout the history of
Earth. Recent analyses have also revealed that on some occasions many species become
extinct at the same time, a mass extinction.
One of the best known examples of mass extinction occurred 65 million years ago,
with the demise of dinosaurs and many other forms of life.
Perhaps the largest mass extinction was the one that occurred 225 million years ago,
when approximately 95 of all species died.
Mass extinctions can be caused by a relatively rapid change in the environment and
can be worsened by the close interrelationship of many species.
One interesting and controversial finding is that extinctions during the past 250
million years have tended to be more intense every 26 million years.
This periodic extinction might be due to intersection of the Earth's orbit with a
cloud of comets, but this theory is purely speculative.
Some researchers have also speculated that extinction may be random.
That is, certain species may be eliminated and others may survive for no particular
reason. A species' survival may have nothing to do with its ability or inability to
adapt. If so, some of evolutionary history may reflect a sequence of essentially
random events. Questions 23 to 25 are based on the recording you have just heard.
What does Dr.
say regarding the vast majority of species in Earth's history at the beginning of
the lecture? What does the evidence from fossils suggest?
What can we learn about the interesting and controversial finding?
This is the end of listening comprehension.